Amit Upadhyay

(Music Educator, Consultant)

Contact: - +91-9811744664. E-Mail: - info.amitupadhyay@gmail.com

Address: - Kishangarh, Vasant Kunj, New Delhi – 110070. India.



My objective

Is to encourage creativity and higher-order thinking in a way that increases participants' performance. It is to obtain a teaching position that utilizes advance teaching methods, including team learning and e-learning. As a music teacher with 25 years of varied experience, there's much I can offer to the music education of our young children. I have more than 18 years of experience in mentoring and music coaching teaching staff in various institutions including Apeejay School, Panchsheel Park, New Delhi, Bloom Public School, Vasant Kunj, New Delhi, and Guitar Studio, (music school). I'm confident that my passion for the teachers' and children's development, together with my skills and experience will enable me to make a significant difference at your esteemed institution."

Profile:

A quick learner who is always ready to learn new styles, having good coordination with other musicians/coworkers/colleagues. An experienced passionate musician, with the ability of casting a musical spell over the audience. Musically performer with vocals and guitar chops – Singing and instrument playing ability. Passionate about music with the natural ability to adjust own style to suit different music.

Specialties:

Develop Individualized and Group Lesson Plans.

Offer Inquiry Based Creative Teaching.

Plan, and Execute Lessons / Modules.

Conduct Corporate Guitar Sessions.

Motivate Students, Build Musicianship Skills.

Help students learn the technicalities of various forms of music, viz. country, blues, jazz, classical, etc...

Work Experiences:

★ Western Music Teacher @ Apeejay School, Panchsheel Park, New Delhi. July 2018 – May 2023.

Have educated students about the fundamental concepts of music theory such as rhythm, melody, pitch and tempo. Developed and presented stimulating lesson plans that cover a

wide range of topics and foster music appreciation. Conducted exercises like vocalization, harmonizing, singing, and playing musical instruments. I have led the rehearsals in preparation for the school's musical performances.

- **★** Western Music Teacher @ Bloom Public School, Vasant Kunj, New Delhi. Aug 2014 May 2018.
- ★ Founder / Music Facilitator @ Guitar Studio May 2003 – Aug 2014.
- **❖** Guitar Instructor @ Mongrace Montessori House 14 May 2014 − 31 July 2014
- ❖ Guitar Instructor @ Aadyant Global School February 2009 June 2009
- ★ Music Facilitator @ Muskaan May 2009 - July 2009
- ★ Music Facilitator @ Sound Of Music May 1996 - January 2000
- ❖ Guitar Instructor @ Panasonic LifeScape December 2010 - April 2011
- **❖** Guitar Instructor @ O&M, Ogilvy & Mather July 2011 November 2011

Professional Qualifications / Certifications:

- ✓ Western Music Theory (Grade 2). Feb 2021.
 - Trinity College, London.
- ✓ Training Workshop on **School Safety & DRR**. (Aug 2020).
 - NIDM, National School Of Disaster Management.
 - Ministry Of Home Affairs, Govt. Of India. New Delhi.
- ✓ The Awakened Citizen Programme, (Year 3) Aug 2020.
 - Ramakrishna Mission, Delhi.
- ✓ The Awakened Citizen Programme, (Year 2) May 2019.
 - Ramakrishna Mission, Delhi.
- ✓ Western Music Theory (Grade 1). May 2019.
 - Trinity College, London.

- ✓ The Awakened Citizen Programme, (Year 1) Oct 2018.
 - Ramakrishna Mission, Delhi.
- ✓ Diploma, Vocal Classical, Sangeet Bhushan (1st Year) 2018-19.
 - Pracheen Kala Kendra, Chandigarh.
- ✓ Diploma, Western Music, (Guitar), 2000 2001
 - Shivankan Kala Mahavidyalaya Varanasi.
- ✓ Guitar Basics and Fundamentals of Music, (Guitar, Piano), 1996 1998
 - Sound Of Music.
- ✓ Introduction to Guitar.
 - Berklee College of Music, Coursera.
- ✓ Developing Your Musicianship.
 - Berklee College of Music, Coursera.

Academic Qualification:

01. Graduation – B.Sc, Chemistry Hons. – **64.5%** – **1998**.

Magadh University, Bihar – B. S. Colleage, Dinapur Cant, Patna.

02. Intermediate (10+2) – I.Sc, – 70.5% – 1995.

Bihar Intermediate Education Council, Patna – Prabhunath Singh College, Chhapra.

03. Matriculation $(10^{th} Board) - 60.2\% - 1993$.

Bihar School Examination Board, Patna – Govt. High School Navsthapit.

Recognised Works / Performances:

- ✓ Performed with Mr. **Raj Mohan**, well known artist from Holland performance held at "**Press Club Of India**" show covered by **Rajya Sabha TV**.
- ✓ Got an opportunity to share stage with renowned musicians' (Kailash Kher, Safaqat Amanat Ali, Ali Zafar, etc.), (rhythm guitar support).
- ✓ Composed different tracks for short films (Padaav & Tathastu) as per demand of film makers.
- ✓ Provided background melodies and music for couple of stage shows.

Freelance Works (Association / Collaboration with):

Elephant SoundSense, iSound, ODA, Anthem Group, GIO India, etc...

Publications:

✓ Press Club Of India show covered by Rajya Sabha TV. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u4SwuTfpGgg

✓ Ashirvachan Magazine (Article).

Authors: Amit Upadhyay, Deepti Naval, Shamshir Rai Luthra, Dr. Shabbi Luthra, Ilona Hucke.

Link - http://ashirvachan.com/group/issue-11-2013/page/guitar-journal-amit-upadhyay Delhi November 5, 2013